<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Misc on Y.Liu&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/misc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Misc on Y.Liu&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>user@example.com (Hugo Author)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>user@example.com (Hugo Author)</webMaster>
    <copyright>Yuchen Liu</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 11:14:26 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/misc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>PAW vs UAW</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/paw-uaw/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 11:14:26 -0500</pubDate><author>user@example.com (Hugo Author)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/paw-uaw/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Recently, I finished reading a book called &amp;lsquo;The Millionaire Next Door&amp;rsquo;. Most of the content is talking about common sense, like how to live a frugal life, which most people have already done. It actually brings out an interesting formula about how to categorize your financial status.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Expected Net Worth = (Age x Annual Income) / 10&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;If your actual net worth is &lt;strong&gt;double than the expected number&lt;/strong&gt;, then you are a &amp;lsquo;PAW (Prodigious accumulator of wealth)&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;If your actual net worth is &lt;strong&gt;less than half of the expected number&lt;/strong&gt;, then you are a &amp;lsquo;UAW (Under accumulator of wealth)&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;If you are something in between, like most people, you are an &amp;lsquo;AAW (Average Accumulator of Wealth)&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;PAW means you live below your means-you are wealthy compared with your lifestyle. Obviously, you should try to be a &amp;lsquo;PAW&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Career Change: From Cybersecurity to Software Development</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/career-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 May 2025 11:46:59 -0400</pubDate><author>user@example.com (Hugo Author)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/career-change/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As a young professional in cybersecurity, do you often feel so dumb that you can&amp;rsquo;t understand some concepts? Maybe my experience can help.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;my-background&#34;&gt;My Background&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I studied Information Security in college. We had the usual foundational CS and math courses, along with cryptography. Back then, the security field seemed straightforward—either you were an attacker or a defender—even though I had no idea how either actually worked.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Later, I interned at two companies, where I learned about web pentesting and Active Directory security. I thought I was cool because I could &amp;ldquo;hack a machine.&amp;rdquo; But I fell into the certification trap and stayed there for years. I believed that once I got my OSCP, I&amp;rsquo;d land a great job and be set for life. The truth? I never passed the exam and I still got a decent job.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
